[音乐]
[MUSIC]
&gt；&gt；道格拉斯：所以这是我对汤普森的最后一件事。
&gt;&gt; Douglas: So this is the last thing I'm going to complain about Thompson.
再一次，我要感谢汤普森，汤普森给了我们Unix，
And again, I have to appreciate Thompson, Thompson gave us Unix,
汤普森给了我们B，这导致了我们所有的现代语言。
Thompson gave us B, which led to all of our modern languages.
汤普森给了我们正则表达式，汤普森给了我们UTF-8，
Thompson gave us regular expressions, Thompson gave us UTF-8,
我认为这是我见过的最聪明的事情之一。
which I think is one of the smartest things I've ever seen.
汤普森给了我们一些惊人的礼物
Thompson has given us some amazing gifts, and
作为专业程序员，我们都欠汤普森很大一笔钱。
as professional programmers, we all owe a tremendous amount to Thompson.
不幸的是，汤普森在编程语言方面的品味很差，在编程方面
Unfortunately, Thompson had terrible taste in programming languages, in programming
语言设计，更糟糕的是，他的影响力非常大。
language design, and even worse than that, he was extremely influential.
所以我们所有人从第一次开始就一直在阅读汤普森的设计
So all of us have been reading Thompson's designs from our first
几个小时的编程。
hours of programming.
我们做了这么久，看起来一切都很好，
And we've been doing it so long, it all looks right to us,
我们看不到这件事有多糟糕，也看不到它对我们的影响有多大。
we cannot see how bad this stuff is and how much it compromises us.
例如，+运算符，这是为了做指针运算，
So for example, the ++ operator, this was added to be for doing pointer arithmetic,
并且我们已经确定指针运算是有害的。
and we have since determined that pointer arithmetic is harmful.
所以我们不再这么做了
So we don't do it any more,
现代语言不支持指针运算。
modern languages do not support pointer arithmetic.
最后一种使用指针算法的流行语言是C+，
The last popular language to have pointer arithmetic was C++,
一种如此糟糕的语言，它是以这个运算符命名的。
a language so bad, it was named after this operator.
&gt；&gt；扬声器2：[laugh]&gt；&gt；Douglas：但是
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: [LAUGH] &gt;&gt; Douglas: But
操作员拒绝死亡，它仍然在我们所有的语言中，
the operator refused to die, it's still in all of our languages,
即使我们不再需要它来增加指针。
even though we don't need it to increment pointers anymore.
所以现在我们用它给变量加1，这是完全不必要的，
So now we use it to add one to variables, which is completely unnecessary,
但我们做到了。
but we do it.
不幸的是，它导致了一种编程风格，在这种风格中，您试图编写一个
And unfortunately, it leads to a style of programming in which you try to write one
衬垫，在里面你试着拿一大堆东西，然后
liners, in which you try to take a whole bunch of stuff and
试着把它挤成一行。
try to smush it down into one line.
这会导致非常糟糕的代码，
And that leads to really bad code,
很难维护，很难纠正的东西。
stuff which is very hard to maintain, very hard to correct.
我们看到了安全错误，缓冲区溢出，诸如此类的事情，
We've seen security errors, buffer overruns, those sorts of things,
这个运算符总是牵涉到这些类型的安全错误中。
this operator is always implicated in those sorts of security errors.
而且我发现在我自己的实践中，任何时候我在任何地方使用+，
And I found in my own practice, any time I use ++ anywhere,
这东西抓住了我，我无法控制它，
this thing takes hold of me, and I can't control it,
它让我想要将代码并尝试将其压缩为一行。
it makes me wanna take code and try to mush it down to one line.
即使我知道这是一件愚蠢的事，我也无法控制自己，
Even though I know that's a stupid thing to do, I can't control myself,
这东西控制了我，我开始写一些非常愚蠢的东西，
this thing takes hold of me, and I start writing really stupid stuff,
以为我真的很聪明。
thinking I'm being really smart.
所以最终，我不得不停下来，因为我做不到一点点。
So eventually, I had to stop because I couldn't do it a little bit.
我必须完全停止。
I had to stop completely.
所以我说不再+了，从现在开始，是+=1，
So I said no more ++, from now on, it's +=1,
我可以放松，这很容易。
and I can relax, and it's easy.
我现在可以写出好的程序了。
I can just write good programs now.
&gt；&gt；道格拉斯：食物味道更好，只是，一切都很棒。
&gt;&gt; Douglas: Food tastes better, it's just, everything's great.
有一段时间，我以为只有我，但现在我推荐大家
And for a while, I thought it was just me, but now I'm recommending everybody
一直都是+=1，每次都是+=1，太棒了，好多了。
+=1 all the time, every time, +=1, it's great, so much better.
但我总是听到人们说，但是
But I hear from people all the time, saying but
我想写x+因为它的意思是一样的，
I wanna be able to write x++ cuz it means the same thing,
而不是必须去，我不能去，我没有那样的时间。
and instead of having to go, and I can't go, I don't have that kind of time.
除了打字时间是不相关的，
Except that the typing time is irrelevant,
这完全无关紧要，我们不会把时间花在打字上。
it is completely irrelevant, we don't spend our time typing.
但更重要的是，它是+x，这意味着和x+=1差不多。
But more than that, it's ++x, which means about the same thing as x+=1.
所以每当我看到有人在增量位置写x+时，我就不得不问，
So any time I see someone writing x++ in increment position, I have to ask,
这个小丑明白增量前后的区别吗？
does this clown understand the difference between pre-increment and post-increment?
这意味着我必须查看他程序中的每个+
And it means I have to look at every ++ in his program and
问他这个答对了吗？
ask did he get this one right?
他这次做对了吗？
Did he get this one right?
因为这是一个小的诵读困难的东西，这真的很难说出来，当你有
Cuz it's a little dyslexic thing, which it's really hard to tell when you've got
它们颠倒了，它导致了一个区域的关闭，这只是一个瞬间的关闭。
them reversed, and it causes an off by one area that's only off for an instant.
但这足以导致bug，而且调试这些东西真的很难。
But that's enough to cause a bug, and it's really hard to debug those things.
支持+的理由是它提高了可读性，这是胡说八道。
The argument in favor of ++ is that it improves readability, which is bullshit.
它没有改善可读性，它改善了模糊性，
It does not improve readability, it improves ambiguity,
它改善了混乱，这是不可取的事情。
it improves confusion, which are things which are not desirable.
所以我在回顾一些代码，我看到了+x，+x，那么那里发生了什么？
So I was reviewing some code and I saw ++x, ++x, so what's going on there?
所以有可能是复制和粘贴错误，除了代码似乎
So it's possible that it was a copy and paste error, except the code seemed to be
工作，所以更有可能，所发生的是有人做了a+x和
working, so more likely, what had happened was someone had done a ++x and
然后其他人注意到，这里有一个问题。
then someone else noticed, there's an off by one problem here.
所以又做了一次，如果原始代码说+=1，
So did it again, if the original code said +=1,
那么显而易见的解决方案是+=2，对吧？
then the obvious solution would be += 2, right?
它提出了一个问题，为什么我们认为我们需要完全不同的
And it raises the question, why do we think we need completely different
将1添加到变量中，然后每隔一个值添加一的语法？
syntax for adding one to a variable, then every other value?
这怎么说得通？
How does that make any sense?
答案是，这没有任何意义，但是
The answer is, it does not make any sense, but
在我们的语言中，我们对糟糕的语法有一种情感上的依恋
there is this emotional attachment we have to bad grammar in our languages
这让我们觉得+就是我，这是我的一部分。
that makes us feel ++ is that's who I am, it's part of who I am.
如果你把+从我身边拿走，我是什么？
If you take ++ away from me, what am I?
还剩下什么？
What's left?
阿华。
Wah.
&gt；&gt；扬声器2：[笑]&gt；&gt；道格拉斯：华。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: [LAUGH] &gt;&gt; Douglas: Wah.
所以没有成本，通过采用更严格的风格，
So for no cost, by adopting a more rigorous style,
可以自动避免许多类别的错误。
many classes of errors can be automatically avoided.
所以我想到了，那么谁的写作风格不好呢？
So it occurred to me, so who's writing with bad style?
所以我想出了四类糟糕的造型师
So I came up with four classes of bad stylists, and
在我的职业生涯中，我不得不在不同的时候承认，我曾经是所有这些人。
I have to confess at various times in my career, I have been all of these people.
所以首先是受教育程度较低的人。
So first are the under educated.
我们在Web开发人员中看到了很多这一点。
We see this a lot in web developers.
我们现在有一些人正在编写JavaScript，他们没有接受过正式的培训
We have people who are writing JavaScript now who received no formal training
在JavaScript中，他们通过查看一些源代码自学了如何做到这一点
in JavaScript, who taught themselves how to do it by doing View Source of some
有史以来最糟糕的代码，
of the worst code ever written,
一路送回Dreamweaver的垃圾复印件，简直是糟糕透顶的东西。
copies of crap going all the way back to Dreamweaver, just awful stuff.
从来没有人告诉过这些人，你可以把这些东西做好，对吧？
And nobody ever told these people, you can do this stuff well, right?
他们从来没有见过好的例子，这只是可悲的。
They've never seen good examples, it's just sad.
然后是老派，非常熟练的人
Then there is old school, people who are extremely skilled and
在一种特定的语言方面有经验，现在环境迫使他们工作
experienced in one particular language, and now circumstances force them to work
在另一个，他们没有相同的知识或经验。
in another one, where they don't have that same knowledge or experience.
我们现在Java和C+人员不得不进入的JavaScript中看到了很多这一点
We see this a lot now in JavaScript that Java and C++ guys are having to go into
JavaScript，因为那里有工作，他们真的很苦恼。
JavaScript because that's where the jobs are, and they're really bitter about it.
他们说好的
And they say okay,
我会写你的JavaScript，但我不可能知道我在做什么。
I'll write in your JavaScript, but there's no way I'm gonna know what I'm doing.
这是原则。
That's principle.
&gt；&gt；扬声器2：[笑]&gt；&gt；道格拉斯：出于某种原因，
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: [LAUGH] &gt;&gt; Douglas: For some reason,
人们对于不知道自己在用JavaScript做什么感觉真的很好。
people feel really good about not knowing what they're doing with JavaScript.
事实上，我们知道编程是一项复杂的业务，而且
In fact, we know that programming is complicated business, and
你永远不想在无知中承担它。
you never want to undertake it in ignorance.
但出于某种原因，我们对JavaScript一无所知感到非常好。
But for some reason, we feel really good about being ignorant about JavaScript.
然后是寻求刺激的人。
And then there are the thrill seekers.
这些人发现了，嘿，你知道你可以把你的分号放在
These are guys who found out, hey, did you know you can put your semicolon at
语句的开头而不是结尾，有时它是有效的？
the beginning of a statement instead of at the end, and sometimes it works?
哇！
Wah!
&gt；&gt；扬声器2：[笑]&gt；&gt；道格拉斯：等
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: [LAUGH] &gt;&gt; Douglas: And so
他们写这种看起来很愚蠢的废话只是因为。
they just write this stupid looking crap just because.
我认为像那样的人在编码时应该戴头盔。
I think people like that should have to wear helmets when they're coding.
最后，暴露狂，这些人会研究标准，
And finally, the exhibitionist, these are people who will study the standard,
研究实现，找到所有奇怪的角落情况，并且
study the implementations, find all the weird corner cases, and
在这种语言中有很多奇怪的，奇怪的角落案例。
there are a lot of weird, bizarre corner cases in this language.
并有意地在他们写的每一件事中使用它们，
And intentionally use them in everything that they write,
你看着然后去的东西，该死的那是什么意思？
stuff where you look at and go, what the hell's that supposed to mean?
他们以此为荣。
And they're proud of it.
他们走了，看看这个，你根本不知道。
They go, look at that, you have no idea.
但他们正在这么做，而且
But they're doing that, and
他们会说那是故意的，我知道我在做什么。
they'll say that was intentional, I know what I'm doing.
我说不，如果你知道自己在做什么，你就不会这么做了。
And I say no, if you knew what you were doing, you would not be doing that.